Touched by Genius. Cursed by Madness. Blinded by Love.
Total Eclipse is a drama, romance film directed by Agnieszka Holland.
Young, wild poet Arthur Rimbaud and his mentor Paul Verlaine engage in a fierce,
forbidden romance while feeling the effects of a hellish artistic lifestyle.
Arthur Rimbaud, played by Leonardo DiCaprio.
Paul Verlaine, played by David Thewlis.
Mathilde Maute, played by Romane Bohringer.
Isabelle Rimbaud, played by Dominique Blanc.
Rimbaud's Mother, played by Nita Klein.
Isabelle, as a child, played by Félicie Pasotti.
Total Eclipse is a 1995 erotic historical drama film directed by Agnieszka Holland, based
on a 1967 play by Christopher Hampton, who also adapted it for the screen.
Based on letters and poems, it presents a historically accurate account of the relationship between
19th-century French poets Arthur Rimbaud (Leonardo DiCaprio) and Paul Verlaine (David Thewlis).
Warner Bros.
has included the film in the catalogue of Warner Archive Collection.
The film explores themes of paris, france, mentor,
poet, biography, based on play or musical.
The tone is emotional.